# **HECTOR VASQUEZ**

FRONT END DEVELOPER ♥ BUENOS AIRES, ARGENTINA 📞 +54 011 51029271

## ° DETAILS °

Buenos Aires Argentina +54 011 51029271 hvasquezdev@gmail.com

#### LINKS

https://hectorvasquez.netlify.app/ https://github.com/Hvasquezdev

# ° SKILLS °

JavaScript

HTML & CSS

Vue.js

Vuex

Nuxt.js

Three.js

React.js

Tailwind.Css

Node.js

Git

TypeScript

## LANGUAGES

Spanish; Castilian

English

## HOBBIES

Learn new things by reading books or blog post, play videogames and also play sports like table tennis or soccer

#### PROFILE

Passionate and innovative Front end developer with about 4 years of professional experience maintaining, building and delivering immersive and engaging user experience, mobile first, accessibility and SEO optimization through Front end web development. Proactive developer learning new things and improving current skills daily. Proeficent with the most modern technologies like modern JavaScript ES6 + / Vue.Js / Nuxt.js / React.Js also knowledge in S.O.L.I.D. principles and software architecture patterns to keep a good organization and maintainability in the front-end code.

Learning everyday is my path to be a better developer.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Frontend at Nea, Remote

November 2022 — Present

- · Creation of new modules following the best practices
- Migration of all services and create new ones following clean code practices
- Refactor of old components and modules
- Fast task completion to allow a fast feature delivery
- · Part of discovery teams to follow new features

#### Frontend at Plerk, Remote

February 2022 — October 2022

- · Fix and refactor of the old modules and pages that are still in use
- Optimization of some module to improve performance, code readability and re-utilization
- Create new big modules/features by using the best practices
- · Fast task completion to allow a fast feature delivery
- Definition of core concepts and rules of new Front-end projects
- Implementation of features, and improving current ones by following the best practices and SOLID principles

#### Frontend at Prendea, Remote

November 2020 — January 2022

Front-end developer to improve and optimize current frontend of the page and also add new features with best practices

- Optimize web pages to better SEO, accessibility and performance
- · Create new pages fully responsive, cross-browser optimized and accessibility
- Fix old responsive design in the existing web pages
- Develop new big frontend features by using best practices
- Fast iteration and tasks completion to allow the team to make tests
- · Refactor and improve current code and frontend architecture
- Connect web apps with an API to fetch and send data

## Frontend at Nextreality Digital, Remote

May 2019 — October 2020

Principal Front-End developer to optimize existing web pages and create new web apps

- Optimize 3D app made with Three.js and A-frame
- · Optimize web pages to better SEO, accessibility and performance
- Create new web apps fully responsive and cross-browser optimized
- · Fix old responsive design in the existing web pages

- Develop new 3D features with Three.js
- Connect web apps with an API to fetch and send data

#### Full-Stack at Contraloria Municipal del Estado Bolívar, Ciudad Bolívar

February 2019 — December 2019

Intranet web app to send internal messages

- Delivered single page app with responsive (Mobile first), cross-browser compatible and performance optimized
- Developed with modern technologies: Vue.js, Tailwind.Css, Node.Js, Socket.io, MySQL, Express.js

#### Frontend at Policia Municipal, Ciudad Bolívar

April 2018 - November 2018

Traffic taxes system

- Developed with Vue.js, Bulma.Css
- · Created accessible, optimized and full responsive mobile first web app
- · Connect Front-end with the database made in PHP and MySQL

#### Frontend at Café Center Restaurant, Ciudad Bolivar

March 2017 — October 2017

Restaurant online reservation system

- · Delivered full responsive web app, cross-browser compatible and accessibility
- · Front-end with vanilla JavaScript and Google material design

#### EDUCATION

Ingeniería Informática, Intitulo Universitario de Tecnología del Estado Bolívar, Ciudad Bolívar

2015 — January 2020

# COURSES

Arquitecto FrontEnd, Platzi

February 2019

Escuela de JavaScript, Platzi

January 2020

Carrera de Vue.Js, Platzi

March 2019

Intermediate React.js, Frontend Masters

March 2020

**JavaScript Hard Parts, Frontend Masters** 

April 2020

Introducción al Desarrollo Web: HTML y CSS, Google

June 2017